# NICHOLAS SEIDL

# Computer Vision - Software Engineer

I have experience in industry working on various **computer vision** and **machine learning** projects. I'm currently working at Apple in their C&P CVML team on various projects, such as face detection. I built a **live object detector (YOLO)** for Wayfair in Summer 2019. In Spring 2019, I worked on **failure analysis** of Apple's Neural Face Detector. In Spring + Summer 2018, I built two **web services** at Apple: one for **content analysis and retrieval** and one for **hosted image comparisons and history**.

## **Contact**

nicholasseidl@gmail.com (650)-739-6674



<u>nseidl.io</u>



/in/nicholaskseidl



github.com/nseidl

# Languages

Python, Java, Javascript, C, C++, Swift

## **Software**

Tensorflow, TensorRT, Keras, TFLite, CoreML, EC2, Tornado, Flask, React, Typescript, Redux, Node, S3, Postgres, Elasticsearch, MySQL, REST, Docker

#### **Courses**

Algorithms and Data Structures Artificial Intelligence Linear Algebra Distributed Systems ML and Data Mining Object Oriented Design Computer Systems Programming Languages Probability and Statistics

#### **Interests**

Board Member of Pool Club, Photography Club, Basketball, Hiking

## **Experience**

Apple Inc.

CVML - Machine Learning Engineer

Cupertino, CA Spring 2020 - Present

•

Wayfair LLC

Boston, MA

Data Science - Computer Vision Engineer

June 2019 - Aug. 2019

- Implemented YOLO(v3) neural network for <u>live on-device object detection</u>
- Optimized with quantization, CUDA, cuDNN, TensorRT, and Tensor Cores
- Achieved 80x speedup in inference time and up to 4x smaller model sizes

Apple Inc.

Cupertino, CA

CVML - Machine Learning Engineer

Jan. 2019 - June 2019

- Analyzed failures of face detector to target aggressors and guide development
- Designed and automated failure analysis pipeline: inference → detection evaluation → failure analysis → visualization
- Curated datasets for different uses with custom model in the loop processes
- Managed data collection, selection, and annotation (guidelines, spec, and quality)

Apple Inc.

IMG QE - Full Stack Software Engineer Jan. 201

Cupertino, CA Jan. 2018 - Aug. 2018

- Content Collection: audio/image/video/stream analysis and retrieval
  - Integrated blob (Amazon S3) and metadata (Postgres) stores to serve content
  - Leveraged Python and Tornado for asynchronous and non-blocking REST API
  - Extracted attributes from audio, image, video, and stream content (Swift)
- Image Comparisons: image comparison web service with history
  - Rewrote backend in Flask; expanded API for frontend and hosted comparisons
  - Modularized backend so different comparison algorithms can easily be added

## **UnitedHealth Group - Optum Technology**

TDP - Backend Software Engineer

Boston, MA Summer 2017

Boston, MA

- Engineered pluggable Blockchain platform; adapted to bank transaction reconciliation and facilitation (big data)
- Designed, implemented, optimized backend and middle-tier pipeline (Python, Bash): MySQL → .csv → JSON → Elasticsearch → Blockchain → Hash Enforcer

#### **Education**

**Northeastern University** 

Sep. 2015 - Dec. 2019 GPA: 3.5 / 4.0

Khoury College of Computer Sciences

Bachelor of Science in Computer Science